[Music]
e
w
[Music]
Hello everybody welcome back to the ask
abijit show it's been a long time I hope
you're all doing very well and I'm so
glad to be back live on this uh
longstanding podcast of mine I hope
you're all doing great so before we get
into any questions as always let me see
who all is live on the live chat and let
me greet you all I can see
AES um Arya bhatacharya himansu Sharma
anop da Mish mes Shivan garit Singh Chan
OAS shush dianu aish again Prat priyan
sud hello hes gorov T5 hajola Singh
adiya Ravi Kumar Abhijit Rd jman Raj
Singh KL prus jatin GK geopolitical dub
hello sir um ma'am manari Dave Aman
vakil sabana hello barno Rik Shri
Krishna Shivam Singh Sagar hello bimla
karik Dr J Shankar Supremacy hello
feminist Impaler Rik kutar Joel yungi
Manor Namaste noad droni LOL no Omer hi
Omer jendra Dr Atul Kar NAD jri shria J
hello the indig gal yes back after a
long time summer pan anud Uncle Sam VI
Mani
900m surender otaku reference prus
hajola Singh Again Sam Gandhi Namaste
monish sabarinath hello J hind uh who
else do we have Uncle Biden 420 Karan
nwat hello
uh I can see s Somalia Paul Surendra
Gupta Ajit aish Gopi sish show J JJ
saraf the beyonder Doga shria DPG sahil
act Dimensions Kash Namaste anuman
bahuguna Shri Kant Sani and so many
other people Sid the
way kumal uh Amir Gardia ches chess
shastra Frank a Costa bik vadera Joseph
Matthew hi after a long time yes
indeed udai Kumar good evening and
everybody else so uh yeah I'm going to
stop greeting you all it's been I think
more than three minutes I've been
greeting you all so let's stop there as
always you all have asked lots and lots
and lots of questions ad G thank you
very much nice to have you online hello
uh yes yes not missing just working and
yeah so uh uh let's see what question
questions we have you all have asked
lots of questions as as always let me
see what do we have
um uh but what we can do is uh there are
lots of people online as well so why
don't we start with some online
questions right and in case there is
some noise in the background please
excuse me for that U this is the festive
season and in here in India people like
to blast music on full Full volume so in
case you're hearing some noise in the
background I would apologize I hope it's
not that audible but yeah so uh let us
take some questions let us say let us
take some questions and see what we have
uh and let's let's talk about first of
all let me put some music in the
background never tried that before but
let me see let me let me put some music
in the background in so that the in case
you're hearing any noise it it will be
dro round out there we go uh and in case
it's too loud let me know and I
will I will try and fix it okay so akat
is saying it's not audible that's great
that's great okay that's
fantastic
um okay let us
see um what what questions do we have
okay so says views on World Cup I think
India is doing well in the World Cup yes
uh I think India is is I think India is
doing reasonably well I think India has
won all of its
matches and it's interesting that in
certain Indian stadiums there is support
for certain themes I mean uh I have not
really followed the Pakistan matches yes
I saw I saw yesterday the South Africa
defeated Pakistan I was like I saw the
last five minutes or so and
uh and uh it's interesting that in
certain stadiums there is a certain
amount of support for teams like
Pakistan and Bangladesh in India which I
find surprising I mean it's it's fine to
support other teams as well when your
team is not playing but for Indians to
support Pakistan or to to wear Pakistan
t-shirts or whatever it's it's I I think
it's not quite right so yeah I found
that surprising I found that surprising
yeah okay
so okay so everyone's saying there's no
music there's no noise in the background
which is great all right fantastic
um Samar aara says why is subsaharan
Africa always in crisis I think we
should see the map for that so that we
understand what what we mean by
subsaharan Africa let me uh quickly put
a map on the screen give me a second or
so as always the map is our best friend
and if you see the map we understand
context so let us bring the map on the
screen let us
yeah so what is subsaharan Africa and
why is this place always in crisis let's
close this
yeah the subsaharan Africa is is
essentially this entire belt above the
green area okay you can see the green
area which you can see Nigeria here
right Nigeria it's kind of green so
above the green area you have this
region called subsaharan Africa it's
it's also called the Sahel the Sahel
region of Africa and you know it's
called the KU wealth in Africa it's
always a place where you have coups lots
of coups I mean if you go to I don't
know whatever online resource you have
and see the list of Cs in the past 10 20
years going to see a whole list of Cs in
in these nations right a very unstable
region you have dictator dictatorships
that are that are propped up in these
nations uh and these are propped up by
the West either by France or or certain
other nations right and recently ner has
been in the news because there's been a
they are a popular coup a coup that's
supported by the population and they've
got rid of the French Ambassador at the
French military from the nation nja
obviously is a nation that is a like
I've spoken on many occasions it's rich
in uh uranium it's one of the top 10
uranium produc producers in the world
and it's one of the major suppliers of
uranium to France I mean the French were
getting uranium from ner at less than a
dollar a kilo yeah when the actual uh
market price is around 150 to $200 so
that's how they were stealing Ur uranium
from ner and now that's kind of come to
an end so why is subsaharan Africa
always in crisis it's like why is the
Middle East always in crisis it's always
an external hand okay so one thing about
Africa that you will notice in this
region is that you have so many straight
line boundaries you know International
borders that have straight lines so
these are borders that were arbitrarily
drawn by the west by the Europeans in
the 19th century and in the 20th century
also arbitrarily to divide up Africa
among themselves so what these straight
line borders do is that they they cut
across you know uh tribal boundaries and
ethnic boundaries so half of you of a
tribe or half of an ethnic group is is
found in one one on one side of the
border and another on the other side of
the Border these are unnatural
nonorganic borders and because of this
you have you know ethnic groups that
typically did not live together who were
forced to live together somehow in one
nation so that causes Civil War Wars and
that's by Design so when you have these
nations that are enrolled in Civil Wars
and ethnic strife and whatnot then you
can install dictators and you can you
know have foreign interference in the
nation in the name of you know bringing
stability and human rights and all
democracy and all that and uh yeah it's
all about resources at the end end of
the day Africa is extremely uh rich in
various kinds of resources natural
resources mineral resources gold uranium
copper whatnot you can IM you can think
of it all and it's all there and so so
the West what it does is is it keeps
these regions these nations in a
constant state of Crisis so that it can
then interfere in the Nations put their
own puppet dictators in place or have un
or whatever other group that comes and
medals in the internal matters of the
nation and by doing all this they're
able to extract natur natural resources
out of the out of the these countries
the French have what they call the CF
Frank which comes in two flavors so it's
the currency that the French government
issues and it is used by a large number
of nations in this region right and that
is one way of controlling the economies
of of these nations uh and this the CF
Frank
has you know a straight conversion rate
with the Euro which the French decide uh
the the the the you know the finances
the ex Checker of these many of these
nations uh they they all the money is
deposited in French Banks so that's how
you have this state of neoc colonialism
neoc colonization that still exists in
Africa in in the in this region
subsaharan Africa and other parts of
Africa as well but subsaharan Africa is
where you have the French who have a
very strong stronghold or strangle hold
in this region and nowadays it's become
you know uh the place where uh you you
are seeing a new manifestations of the
new Cold War in this region because the
Russians have got involved the Chinese
have been for the past 10 20 years so a
lot going on so just like the Middle
East it's an artificial crisis that's
been induced and kept going on in
perpetuity for decade and decade and
decades right and in both cases it's the
West that is responsible for that so
that is a a brief overview of of how
things are in this region so yeah good
question now let's uh see something
else um
okay nsh says what's the status of Tibet
now where is Tibet let's let's take a
look at Tibet where is Tibet in case
some of us don't know let me uh put that
on the screen where is Tibet okay let's
make it little larger Tibet is this
region north of India it was historical
historically called b d
b uh I don't know why it's called Tibet
the westerners have decided to mangle
all Eastern names yeah so so it's
called Uh Tibet so what's the status
it's under is occupation right that's
the status of Tibet uh the Tibetans have
become a minority in their own land you
have the Chinese Communist Party flag
that flies over Lassa over the poala
palace the
Tibetans they are slowly being you know
their culture is being wiped out their
language is being wiped out their
children are forced to to do their
schooling in in Chinese and the Chinese
Mandarin language so so yeah that's
that's what's happening that's the stup
of Tibet right now Tibet historically
has been a a nation that's been a buffer
between India between two great
civilizations India and China CH China
has historically never had any right any
claim whatsoever on Tibet but right now
they have claimed it because because of
of the uh decisions taken by the nean
government in the 1950s to a large
extent they allowed this to happen so
that's the status of Tibet right now
Tibet is a nation under occupation and
it's being slowly squeezed to death
essentually yes that's what Sager says
Le
that is true it is very true the French
are prosperous because of Africa because
of the wealth and resources they extract
Out of
Africa um uh okay what else do we
have
um okay Kash Kash says what are your
views on India's no vote extension in
the recent U Hamas conflict there was a
vote yesterday or day before yesterday
in the UN about some resolution and
India abstained in this us said don't
stop I don't care what the US says what
did India do India abstained so I think
it was something about condemning Israel
or something or the other and India
stayed out of it so I think see look uh
what's happening in the Middle East in
in it's it's uh it's unfortunate uh
clearly Hamas started it okay I don't
care what anyone says if it upsets
people so be it it was started by Hamas
and
uh with their act of horrific terrorism
that the perpetrated on the on the on
the people of Israel and then Israel has
retaliated maybe they have retaliated
excessively or not you know in in these
things in geopolitics in in in Warfare
there is no right there is no wrong it's
only about who can Prevail uh so India
has I think wisely stayed out of this uh
as soon as this act of terrorism by
Hamas happened the prime minister of
India was very clear he went on Twitter
and said that we he called this an act
of terrorism right and he clearly said
that India stands with Israel so I think
that's o overall India's official stand
historically India has had kind
of some kind of sympathy towards the uh
aspirations and all that of the
Palestinian people but you know you
can't resort to terrorism so that's
what's happened and I think India is
doing a wise thing by staying out of
this conflict not picking one side or or
the other we don't have a horse in this
race we don't have a dog in this fight
with all due respect to both sides so I
think yeah India India is is is doing
the right thing by not taking sides and
staying out of it but obviously India
will always unequivocally condemn any
Act of terrorism no matter who does it
and what Hamas did was an act of
horrific terrorism and India clearly
stood with Israel
uh or
that
okay om beiker raises an important
question what can India do to free eight
Navy veterans from Qatar so what's the
deal with Qatar okay lots of people are
very upset with good reason so first of
all where is Qatar let's take a look at
Qatar we have to always use the map to
orient ourselves we know where India is
now let's uh look in India's extended
neighborhood okay go westwards you have
the Gulf of you have the Sea of sashtra
which is erroneously called the Arabian
Sea then you have what they call the
Gulf of Oman and then you have the
Persian Gulf in the Persian G Persian
Gulf over here West Northwest of the UAE
we have Qatar this nation this little
Nation over here okay so this tiny
little nation that is smaller than Sri
Lanka uh has
uh has uh first of all they've been
holding these eight uh Indian Navy
veterans in prison for over a year and
this week it's been announced that uh it
has been announced that uh they have
sentenced these eight Indian Navy
veterans to death and apparently the
charge is that they the charge is that
they have accused them of spying on
behalf of Israel okay that's the
thing so uh yeah so that is the
situation that we find ourselves in now
lots of Indians are angry because Qatar
is this tiny little Nation smaller than
Sri Lanka and it is it is you know
taking such actions against an enormous
large Nation like India and people are
saying that the Modi government has
failed and they are able to do nothing
in even if a small tiny Nation does this
we are able to do nothing we have to
understand the big picture perspective
over here what is the significance of
Qatar in world affairs right uh what
what is Qatar standing in the
world
so first of all you may remember the
2022 World Cup football World Cup took
place in this Nation Qatar so this tiny
apparently insignificant nation which is
actually a nation which a very hot
climate not suitable for for for
football was able to win you know the
rights to host the World Cup
2022 so understand that when it comes to
events like big Global events like the
Olympics the football World Cup and so
on so forth when a nation is awarded
this it's it's essentially kind
of uh you could say a reward for certain
service that this nation has offered to
the big powers to the great powers and
when it comes to the so-called rules
based World Order and all that the great
power is the
us and we also have to remember that
Qatar is a nation that hosts the US
military on its territory okay there's
at least one US military
base on Qatar territory Qatar is also
the nation that has hosted the the The
Diplomatic talks between the United
States and the Taliban regime before
Afghanistan was handed over back to the
Taliban okay so Qatar has was part of
that Qatar was the place where all of
this happens happened Qatar is so so
Qatar has and and if you look at the
past 20 30 years of History Qatar has
always participated um in in various US
military operations whether it is the
first G War the second G War you know
the US invasions of Iraq which happened
uh in the '90s and the and 2003 if I'm
not mistaken Qatar has participated in
that so Qatar essentially is a nation
that has historically provided a great
amount of service to the United States
you can think of it as a US wasal state
as one of the United States key vasal
States and Qatar is is one of the major
exporters of global exporters of of
liquefied natural gas LNG um India I
think receives about half of its LNG
from Qatar okay and India has a
significant expatriate population in
Qatar I don't know how how many lakhs
maybe four five lakhs I don't remember
the exact figures go and look it up okay
so so Qatar even though it is a tiny
apparently insignificant
Nation okay it it it has the full
backing so to say of the United States
of America and when you have the backing
of a of of a superpower then you can
afford to do certain things so then the
question is why did Qatar do this I mean
clearly this is see first of all Qatar
is not a nation that executes people
routinely okay it's very rare for them
to execute anybody uh so they have you
know imposed a death penalty on on eight
Indian Naval veterans this is a pressure
tactic of some kind on India and who
where is the pressure coming from it's
clearly not coming from Qatar Qatar is
is is a tiny Nation um it's it's it's
merely a Pawn on the larger geopolitical
chess board and who is holding that pawn
is the question it most likely is the US
okay so India in recent times has scored
a number of Victories the G20 was a big
win for India India obviously is rising
economically the US needs India as as a
counterweight to China but the but the
United States is also quite wary of
India okay India is a nation that is
it's the only major nation is the only
major economy that has zero chance of
recession which means India is going to
keep growing steadily at a good at a
good percentage at a good rate for the
next 10 20 years okay and if India keeps
on growing it's 7 8 9 % maybe even 5
six% per year for the next 20 years
India is going to become a genuinely
major economy and and a genuinely great
world power okay so the US doesn't want
to repeat the mistake it did with China
it sees India as a long-term threat on
the long-term Horizon by by 2040 India
could be the next future China you know
that's what they worry about so they
would like to keep India down so they
will they will cooperate with India and
collaborate with India when it comes to
various things that uh involv
countering China because India also
needs a counterweight to India also
needs you
know any support it gets against China
so when it comes to things like the quad
various Indo Pacific initiatives and so
on the US will cooperate with India but
the US will also oppose India and hamper
India and hinder India's growth in a
number of ways so that's the kind of
dual game or or complex game they are
playing when it comes to India okay uh
so when this sort of thing happens when
a tiny insignificant nation has the
tarity to impose the death penalty on
eight Indian Naval veterans what happens
the people of India we know are very
emotional they'll say oh it's a failure
of the Modi government Modi is weak blah
blah blah what foreign policy blah blah
blah okay so so that's the objective
it's to make this government look weak
why because we have 2024 coming up and
India needs a political continuity India
needs political stability if you have a
coalition government that comes up then
it's going to be a disaster for India
because India will not be able to pursue
a strong robust foreign policy and a
strong robust Economic Policy so they
would love the Americans and the Chinese
as well would love to see a weak
government come to power in 2024 in
India so how do you make this happen you
take a number of actions that make the
current government look weak and you do
things that are out of the control of
the Indian government so you take some
random people in Qatar who are working
in some company in Qatar you imprison
them after one year you impose a death
and then it makes the government of
India look weak well you know what as
India Rises this is going to be this is
going to happen more and more okay
there's going to there's going to be
push back from people from from forces
that do not do not want to see India
rise and India has an enormous diaspora
millions of Indians who live and work
all across the world it's going to be so
easy to Target Indians okay outside of
India so they won't do it most likely in
the west because the West believes in
the rule of law blah blah blah but they
will use this Rogue States Rogue actors
like Qatar and God knows what to to keep
on pressurizing India so this is the
price that you pay when you start Rising
okay so India needs to have the appetite
to take to to to be able to you know
withstand all this instead of getting
all emotional and wishy-washy and and
weepy weepy oh this happened that
happened come on grow up this is what
happens So eventually India will have to
take certain actions so for example when
they went imprisons a Chinese let's say
you know high ranking Chinese official
of some of some Chinese company what the
Chinese do is that they will imprison
two three Western business people in
China on Trump dub charges okay so U so
obviously uh that's something we can't
do with when it comes to Qatar because
it's such a tiny Nation we we may have
maybe 12 qataris on Indian Territory or
whatever right so uh even India will
have to come up with ways of dealing
with this but I would not say that this
is a a failure of the government I mean
any Rogue Nation can imprison 12 Indians
somewhere and India cannot start
invading Every Nation right every nation
has its own laws and all that and India
also if you look at Indian prisons we
have citizens of other nations in our
presence so this is something that is
going to happen I I would imagine it
will happen more and more as India
starts Rising India keeps rising and the
world gets really prickly and jealous
about this they're going to try and pull
these pull pull these stunts you know to
make the Indian government look weak so
this is something that India will have
to learn how to deal with so that's
where we are what can India do to free
these eight people from Qatar right now
we can um you
know I'm sure we will ask them to follow
the rule of law we can uh engage them
diplomatically try and put pressure in
some way or the other um so I'm sure
there are various diplomatic means uh
various means that we have at our
disposal diplomatic means and maybe some
other means as well I would not say we
have to go take military action for 12
for 12 people um but yeah we will have
to find some way of dealing with this
okay
right a good question harsh says Qatar
has been providing monthly Aid to Hamas
how does this benefit Qatar and all this
so yeah the Hamas leadership is based in
Qatar okay
which which tells you Qatar
is an important proxy for various uh
maybe excuse me for the US perhaps or
for somebody else so so the Middle East
is constantly in turmoil the Hamas
leadership is Living in Qatar the top
leadership they're living in luxury
while you know what's happening in Gaza
people are being bombed by the
Israelis and the leadership lives in
Gaza uh how does this benefit Qatar well
you
see like I said the Middle East is
constantly in crisis just like Western
Africa the sahil region is constantly in
crisis and all of this crisis is
engineered from outside of these regions
it's the West it's the it's the West
that wants these regions to be always in
crisis so that they can extract
geopolitical benefits out of it so when
you have so let's say the US wants the
Middle East to be constantly in crisis
so they need a good guy they need a bad
guy for them the official good guy is
Israel and the official bad guy is Hamas
and Hezbollah and Iran and so on so
forth now see Hamas it is based in the
Gaza Strip which has a 50 roughly 50
kilometer border with Israel if the top
Hamas leadership were to live in Gaza it
would be very easy for the Israelis to
take them out you know because Israelis
are known to Target you know and
assassinate to do target targeted
assassinations of anti-israel forces the
best way to to prevent that from
happening is to Encon the top top
leadership of Hamas and Qatar where they
they are kind of Out Of Reach of Israel
and since Qatar is a small territory it
there is a good security there and and
and everything can be monitored properly
so yeah so I would say that you know the
US has a history there a very long
history of playing both sides I mean
they W they are the ones who created
Osama bin ladin they are the ones who
created Saddam Hussein okay let's not
even talk about Al-Qaeda and the black
flags and and and Isis let's not even go
there so the Americans have a long
history of playing both sides when it
sooths them terrorists will become
Freedom Fighters and resistance Fighters
and moderates and when it doesn't suit
them they they have to be smoked out and
and and you know dealt
with uh so I I I think it would it is
not beyond the US to even ensure that
the Hamas stop leadership stays in
safety in Qatar while keeping the entire
middle east region Up in Flames so
that's what I would say you know all
right um after this Israel Hamas
conflict is over will we see changed
International map boundaries with no
disputed territories remaining anymore
there you will never ever have settled
International boundaries you will never
ever have all territorial disputes
anywhere settled okay it's it's never
ever going to happen if you look at the
past 2,000 years of History which is a
small of overall history you will find
that International B boundaries and
borders always constantly change they
don't change on a week to week basis but
they change on a decade to decade basis
if you look at the borders over a
century just a century not even 2,000
years you will see changes whether it is
India whether it is Afghanistan whether
it's the Middle East whether it is
Central Asia whether it is North and
South America whether it is the US
Mexico border whatever it always keeps
changing so whenever this Israel Hamas
conflict is over you will most likely
see some changes most likely in in some
of these borders because it is a quite
it is a distinct possibility if the
great powers are not careful that this
conflict which is currently
waging between Israel and Hamas and
maybe Israel and hasbullah it may
suddenly expand Beyond this territory
okay because uh there is going to be a
significant Temptation among Ong the
Islamic world to take action against
Israel especially
if if the people of Gaza suffer too much
okay and there is this you know the
Islamic world is not a unified
monolithic block they have lots of
frictions they have lots of Divisions
they have lots of rivalries they have
lots of conflict conflicts among
themselves okay look at the history
since 1950 you will see that they fight
each other all the time so three of the
so there is uh you know there is this uh
this this competition right now and it's
always been there there is this
competition for the leadership of the
Islamic world who will take up the
leadership and who will Proclaim
themselves the leaders of the Islamic
world so who are the candidates one is
obviously Iran the regime of the ayat
they would like to take up the mantle of
the leaders of the Islamic world the
other obviously candidate is Saudi
Arabia you know the traditional home of
Islam um the king of Saudi Arabia is the
protector of the of the of Mecca and Med
right so there is that then you have
turkey turkey I don't know what they
call themselves nowadays turkey or
whatever so they are they were the last
great Islamic power the Ottoman Empire
and they would love to see that happen
again the the Ottoman Empire to be
revived and then we also have Egypt that
also has at some point in history okay
held the caliphate so we have four
powers let's say Iran Saudi Arabia Egypt
and turkey and they don't all get along
together they there is significant
rivalry and jealousy among these guys so
when you have the this this situation
where Gaza is under siege and Israel the
yehudis are bombarding Gaza they were
one of these nations would love to take
the first step in you know smashing
Israel but obviously it's not it's
easier said than done Israel is not some
pushover Israel is a very powerful
Nation okay in this
region so
if if uh the Nations the the the great
powers are not careful this could very
rapidly expand this war could very
rapidly expand Beyond where it is right
now and if one of these big Nations gets
involved everybody else will will want
to rush in and that's going to be a
disaster okay it's going to it's going
to be a disaster for the world for the
world economy and so on so yeah that's a
deal so uh even if borders change
there's still going to be disputes okay
there are still going to be disputes
that that is is that is a
given right
um what the sun eater says are we
sleepwalking into World War II if we are
not careful we will Sleepwalk into into
I don't know if it will be World War I
but it's going to be a larger conflation
beyond the region where it is right now
the East Bank of the Mediterranean it's
it's GNA it's could it could very
rapidly expand beyond that especially if
Iran gets involved or turkey gets
involved turkey is always tempted to get
involved in various things you know they
are a very aggressive belligerant
nations with huge outsize Ambitions of
Reviving The of the Ottoman
Empire so yeah we need to be very
careful India needs to be very prudent
about all this stay out of this conflict
don't take sides condemn terrorism on
principle but don't take sides over here
and yeah yep yep that's a deal we we
have to be careful otherwise we will
sleep sleep walk into ww3 which we do
not want at all please we don't want
that
okay pain pain says is Russia's
Hypersonic missile capacity and China's
Naval power Superior to that of America
look um good question so the Americans
were the pioneers of hypersonic missiles
um of hypersonic missiles what's a
Hypersonic missile I think it's
typically Beyond mark five okay Mark
Mark 1 means equal to the speed of sound
Mark 2 means twice the speed of sound uh
supersonic is is Mark one and Beyond I
think Hypersonic if I'm not mistaken is
Mark five plus okay and then you have
re-entry speeds ballistic speeds like
mac 23 and all that which is what the
agne and various other ballistic
missiles achieve on re-entry that's a
whole different story so when we talk
about Hypersonic missiles we're talking
about cruise missiles so we have brahmos
which is a supersonic missile it's
typically Mark 2 or thereabouts okay
that's the speed of the brahmas missile
and it's so large and it's got such a
huge momentum that even if you don't put
a warhead on the missile just the impact
of the missile at Mac 2 can slice a ship
into two clean pieces okay so um then we
have missiles like the the the ciron
missile the Russian ciron missile we
have uh what else do we have kinal and
all that so these are the ciron for sure
is a Hypersonic missile Mark 8 Mark 9
kind of thing so the Russians have been
investing I mean you not testing this
technology perfecting this technology
the Americans had this technology and
they kind of Shel it they kind of
shelved it and right now they are not
able to produce hypersonics that's the
sense that I get okay so Russia clearly
is a of the US when it comes to
Hypersonic missiles the Chinese Also may
have Hypersonic missiles maybe maybe I
don't remember exactly what the status
is but they may they definitely will be
working on that they have the dong Fang
missiles the so-called carrier kill
killer missiles
and so on so that's about hypersonics
it's it's a pretty clear that Russia is
ahead of the US when it comes to
Hypersonic missile technology uh where
is India in this we have supersonic
missiles like the brahmos we are working
on the brahos Next Generation NG the
brahmos 2 and whatnot so I sure there
will be U you know the the future
variants of brahos are most likely going
to be Hypersonic sure okay we're also
working on certain other missiles which
would also have Hypersonic speed now
when it comes to China's Naval power the
Chinese have been investing in their
Navy since the early 90s okay in the
early '90s their Navy the Americans
consider the Chinese Navy to be a joke
haaha we can give them a very bad
afternoon and that will be the end of
the Chinese Navy but the Chinese have
been steadily building up their Navy
these days they are in a position to
churn out destroyers and warships like
sausages you know so uh they probably
have the largest Navy in the world the
China Chinese today numerically speaking
okay and they also have this
uh the the uh what do you call it the
Coast Guard Fleet in the Merchant Navy
Merchant Merchant Fleet that also kind
of doubles up the Chinese Navy so they
you can you
know you can take any kind of ship any
kind of surface vessel and put soldiers
on it or you know machine guns on it and
and you can even you know Jerry Jerry
man Jerry rig a a reasonably decent
sized Merchant vessel and put missiles
you know uh anti-ship missiles or
whatever missiles on it the Chinese have
been doing that so if you look at it
numerically the Chinese have probably
the world's largest navy I'm not sure
still if China is still there when it
comes to The lethality of the Navy when
it comes to the actual lethality and and
and capacity of a Navy you don't count
the number of ships you count the number
of missiles it can deploy at any given
point in time okay so from that
perspective the Chinese are kind of
perhaps neck to neck with the Japanese
and maybe perhaps
still be below the capacity of the US
Navy perhaps okay they also they they
they do have these vs tub 64 and all
that on various warships various
destroyers they have very large
destroyers as well so they are obviously
you know quantity has a quality of its
own like Joseph Salin used to say so uh
the Chinese are are following the dictum
and uh I think very soon at least in in
the region that the Chinese are
interested in they will have they
already have numerical superiority so
the region they're interested in is the
Champa sea which is erroneously called
the South China Sea okay they want this
entire region to be a Chinese Lake and
they obviously want thawan so this is
where they are focusing and they are
also worried about Japan Japan has a
tremendously scary Navy from the Chinese
perspective okay South Korea is a US
possession so the US Navy and various
assets will be there so the Chinese are
worried about that you know the the
standard
old island chain terminology the the
three Island chains that they worry
about all the way to
Guam uh where is Guam okay Guam is
somewhere out here uh not this far
somewhere here where is Guam here is
Guam yeah here is Guam okay not that far
so three Island chains that the Chinese
worry about and that's why they are
pushing out you know turnning out
warships like sausages
uh but the good thing for India is that
they are all tied up over here because
of the very strong us presence there
because of the very strong Japanese Navy
and the the the question the problem of
Taiwan Philippines also um these days
they have acquired certain very
interesting weapons like supersonic
missiles from a nation not far from
India so uh yeah that's the deal
Indonesia Also may want certain
supersonic anti-ship
missiles so I think um The Americans
have have kind of uh missed a few tricks
in the past couple of decades you know
they were full of hubris after 1991
after the breakup of the USSR there was
this unipolar moment that was that
extended all the way into the 2010s
until 2012 2015 or so but now there are
big big threats for the US on the
horizon the Russians have stolen a March
when it comes to Hypersonic missile
technology the Chinese have a huge navy
now okay so yeah that's the deal so that
is indeed the the challenges that the US
faces right
now okay okay let's see theas what does
theas have to say hi theas so India had
relations with other countries in the
past Egypt Rome and others are known to
have knowledge about SE routs then why
did vasod the Gama and others why were
they finding routes to India okay good
question let's take a look at the map
all over again so when we talk about
Egypt Egypt is right here okay it's not
really far far from
India well so Egypt in the old days
Egyptian civilization it kind of
extended into Sudan and all that and uh
to to to travel from India to Egypt
there are two major ways of doing it
first is Overland you go so historically
Pakistan was India you go west of
Pakistan we we enter Iran which is still
kind of more or less part of the Indian
subcontinent and a very you could say
you know very similar culture and all
that so you go west from Iran you enter
Mesopotamia and then you at the doll
stop of Egypt so you can just walk over
to Egypt it will take you maybe a couple
of months okay if you are if you are
walking from India with a number of
people and a number of cattle it may
take you a month or two to reach Egypt
if you walk a decent distance every day
and you're reasonably fit the other way
is to go by sea and Indians obviously
were good Sailors so then you would go
from what we call the Gulf of a and the
Red Sea and then you would reach uh
Egypt so the Egyptians obviously traded
with India it's well known we have the
introduction introgression of Indian
zebu cattle in Egypt 2,000 BC which is
4,000 years before today so ancient
relations with with Egypt with
Mesopotamia it's right here we can just
walk there right and we know that India
traded with Rome we have found lots of
Indian artifacts in Rome in herculanum
in Pompei and so on um so when it comes
to going to Rome Indians would probably
not have taken the land route they would
have taken the sea route okay uh
possibly and uh
and and use the Mediterranean Sea to
reach there okay let's not go into the
specifics of of exactly what route they
would have
taken so now what happened why did vasod
the Gama and others have to find a route
to India
so majorly the the trade that happened
between India and Europe it happened via
land so it would be the land route okay
probably between the Black Sea and the
Caspian Sea go why the Caucasus and
enter Eastern Europe and then go all the
way to the to Western Europe so we had
well established land route land land
route between India and the Western
World and and Europe so the the the
event that precipitated this need for
vasod dama and others to find an
alternate SE route that event was the
introgression of these nomadic tury
tribes tribes people into the Anatolia
and and
this region which is now called turkey
the Turks did not live there the Turks
were a Central Asian nomadic people okay
closely U genetically and culturally you
know allied with the mongolic peoples
and at some point in time in the past 15
1200 years the Turks became
islamized and that kind of gave them
Rocket Fuel to go and Conquer everywhere
and uh about which year was the fall of
Constantinople
uh whichever whichever year that was I
think it was in uh in the 15th century
1453 was it the fall of Constantinople
which was the culmination of the turkic
invasions of this region so once the
Turks once the turkic tribes took over
Anatolia and what we now call turkey and
established their their empire the
Ottoman Empire that Empire you see the
Turks were very hostile to the Europeans
okay and they cut off the land route
between India and Europe and that is why
the Europeans were forced to now start
looking for an alternate route to India
and in those days we did not have the Su
Canal you know between Port Sid and ALU
it's an it's an artificial Canal so uh
they were forced to look for an
alternate sea route to India and
christophor Colombo went looking for
India in the wrong direction he ended up
discovering you know becoming I mean he
didn't Discover it it was already there
there were people living there but he
was the first let's say European
Christian first Christian okay to to
discover the Americas before Christopher
Columbus the Vikings obviously the
Nordic Travelers they did discover North
America they they found uh they had a
settlement in L
omido in North the northeast of of North
America and so on that's a whole
different story so Christopher Columbus
was looking for India he ended up
discovering the Americas for the
Europeans and obviously eventually vasod
theama found the land route the the sea
route to India with the help of an
Indian sailor and that's the story okay
so so that is the reason why even though
in ancient times you had trade between
India and Egypt trade between India and
Mesopotamia tra between India and Rome
but because of the cutting off of the
land route by the Ottomans that's why
they were forced to find a long Circus
route sea route to
India
okay gaming lover says will India be a
car Centric Society or a public
transportation based society you know
India has a population of 1.4 billion
India is an enormous Nation if everybody
has a car or even one family has a car
imagine the number of millions of cars
you will on the streets okay and imagine
the kind of pollution it gives out and
imagine how congested the roads will be
I think India should invest in very
efficient public transportation systems
that are
comfortable enjoyable and get you to the
to your destination on time we have
these cities you know like for one
example is Bangalore Bangalore is a
beautiful city great climate but you
know it's a small town that organically
grew big and became a Global Hub of the
IT industry and and startups and all
that but the streets are so narrow that
it's it's very difficult to travel in
Bangalore by by by Road and everybody
obviously wants to have a car of their
own and see that that creates so many
problems so ideally what you should have
is very good public transport maybe
Metro maybe underground Railway or
whatever yeah which is highp speed very
comfortable a pleasant experience and
we'll get you on there on time and if it
can you know cater to the entire
population of large cities I mean
nothing like it so I would say that you
know every Indian aspires to have a car
and all that please don't do that but
yeah unless you have no option you will
have to get get a car right so I think
uh over time the Indian government will
have to find solutions that uh eliminate
the need for people to buy private
transportation and hopefully go towards
public transportation that is great that
is really
enjoyable pleasant experience and and
quick and fast
yeah uh J Arjun says what about Chinese
occupied Mongolia and how Chinese Han
Dynasty people suppressed Mongolian
language and culture well that's a very
long story but yeah you are absolutely
right if you look at the map you know
there is a significant part of Mongolia
that is under Chinese occupation they
the Chinese call it inner Mongolia let's
let's search it for it inner
Mongolia it's part of China so what
reason I don't know
so okay so they're not demarketing the
boundaries Google is kind of aiding
China in this uh so yeah I would say
roughly half of Mongolia is currently
under Chinese occupation okay and
obviously over there it's the Chinese
language that rules the roost so if
you're a Mongolian kid in inner Mongolia
you have to learn the Chinese language
and your schooling most likely is going
to be in the Chinese language and you're
going to be taught the Chinese Communist
Party valleys of atheism and all that
they will suppress Mongolian Buddhism
and all that must be happening uh I I
even remember seeing in the news a few
years AG like in not a very long time
ago the Chinese government was trying to
suppress any any any any mentions of the
great conqueror Shri chingis Khan and so
on the Chinese are very worried about
any uh research on the popularity of
Shir chingis Khan I wonder why maybe
because he conquered China and smashed
the and smashed the Chinese Empire and
created his own Chinese dynasty a
conquest Dynasty the the the Yuan
Dynasty
so on so yes you are right roughly half
of Mongolia is currently under Chinese
occupation and I I hope that they also
get their land back and their freedom
back uh so if you look at China it's an
enormous Nation today but a very
significant portion of this land is just
territory that's been conquered by the
Chinese Communist Party under maum uh
yeah so that is indeed the case and you
are
right
um okay what else do we have um Samar
Gandhi says is Iran trying to use the
engineered crisis in the Middle East for
nuke sneak out what is Iran planning to
do further us conducting another nuclear
test already sounds scary I'm not sure
if the US has conducted a nuclear test
or if they're planning to do so uh look
if the Americans or any of the Great
Powers goes ahead and conducts a nuclear
test today it's going to be a green
signal for everyone to go ahead and do
it so I'm sure the US will take that
into
consideration uh so the main question is
about Iran is Iran trying to use the
crisis in the Middle East for a new
sneak out so once again let's go to the
Middle East and see the map to orient
ourselves Iran is our great neighbor I
mean big neighbor I mean currently we
have a temporary nation in between but
historically it's been our neighbor for
the past uh four 5,000 years so uh Iran
as we know is an aspiring nuclear power
they have a nuclear program and uh the
objective of the nuclear program whether
people like it or not is to build
nuclear weapons Iran wants to become a
nuclear weapons power okay and the
Americans and the Iranians had this deal
the the uh jcpoa joint comprehensive
plan of action which Mr Trump walked
away from unilaterally so that gave Iran
the what
what it freed up Iran to go and and
resume its attempts to to enrich uranium
to weapons grade quality and they've
been doing it for quite some time they
have you know these these facilities
these Cent refuges that that process
uranium hexo fluoride and and you know
enrich uranium okay and it's been going
on for quite quite a few years the
Americans have tried various means of
preventing the Iranians from doing this
from from uh obtaining sufficient you
know enrich uranium uranium you had the
stack net virus that they had introduced
into these facilities like natans Etc so
my point is Iran is an aspiring nuclear
power and they have been enriching
uranium for quite some time it I think
it is possible they may have sufficient
enriched uranium for a nuke or two they
definitely will have sufficient
radioactive material file material to
construct what is called a dirty bomb so
dirty bomb is not a nuclear device the
explosive material in a dirty bomb is
conventional explosive okay but it what
you do is instead of shrapnel you add
some radioactive material to the bomb so
that when it explodes it kind of
vaporizes the radioactive material and
disperses it over a large area like you
could a terrorist organization
organization could do it in a city and
contaminate the whole city and you know
create huge problems
so Iran definitely will have enough
radioactive material to build a few
dirty bombs but they may also have
possibly sufficient enriched uranium to
maybe you know
assemble a a couple of nukes maybe two
or three tactical nukes you know
tactical five I don't know 10 20 kiloton
Hiroshima level bombs they may have it
okay uh and that's what makes this
entire crisis very so so very dangerous
because uh you see what's happening is
that Israel has been the past couple of
years sending
ammunition uh to Ukraine as we may have
forgotten but there's this war going on
in Ukraine right and and the entire
Western world has been supplying Ukraine
with arms and ammunition and Israel has
also sent ammunition to Ukraine because
of which Israel May perhaps be low on
ammunition and if Israel faces the
prospect of a two-front war with Hamas
in Gaza and Hezbollah in southern
Lebanon okay and if other nations get
involved in this then Israel May
suddenly find itself in a very tight
spot where it's running out of
ammunition and then what does it do in
such a situation they could ask their
great benefactor the US to Target some
of these nations and that could you know
lead to a confrontation military
confrontation ktic confrontation between
between the US and Iran and Iran is not
a pushover Iran has sufficient
quantities of weapons and ammunition
they have been supplying Russia with
drones and loitering Munitions in the
war against Israel proxy war over there
so Iran is not quite a pushover and if
the US starts any military action with
Iran Iran May Target various US military
bases in the region including in Qatar
right um and that would make things very
difficult for the US and for Israel
and if Israel find itself finds itself
in a position where its very existence
is in under threat then they always have
what they call the Samson option okay so
Israel is an Undeclared nuclear weapons
power everyone knows they have nukes
maybe 7080 nuclear weapons maybe 100 we
don't know the number okay but it's
roughly around 7080 maybe 100 and if
they find themselves in a situation
where they're about to be overrun they
could go nuclear and they could hit all
these
nations and if there's a nuclear
exchange if let's say they they nuke
Iran and Iran has let's say two or three
nukes they're going to lob them back at
Israel and this could start a nuclear
exchange and when when we're talking
about Iran Iran is part of Coalition
that involves Russia as well as China so
if Iran is targeted you could get you
could have Russian involvement in this
matter Russia as we know have been uh
are are the benefactors of the Assad
regime in Syria the Americans if they
had their way they would have you know
taken Assad out and installed a puet
regime in Syria the Russians prevented
that from happening there was this
terrible civil war in Syria we all know
what's happened in the past 10 15 years
which kind of spilled over everywhere in
this region um the Latakia base where is
it Latakia is a big Naval Base where you
have a significant Russian presence so
this is a complex geopolitical and
Military environment a misstep here or
there could could
you know bring in a much larger conflict
that involves powers that don't really
belong here but they are
here uh yeah so so that's the the
situation quite complex and that's just
where we are right
now
okay H says temples in India have always
been in the control of the government
what's your opinion on this the
government has no business controlling
temples okay the government does not
control the places of worship of other
religions of the of the so-called
minority religions or the so Islamic
places of worship the government has no
say in that the you know they stay out
of it when it comes to other religions
like sik dharm or J DH or bodha dharm or
or the other abrahamic religion
Christianity the government stays out of
their places of worship but when it
comes to us the major civilizational
religion that came out of India what is
called Hinduism Hindu Dharma the
government control the places of worship
and extracts all the money out of them
whatever people donate this is an
Abomination that's why I have always
said that India is the most Hindu phobic
nation in the world and Hindus are
second class citizens or I don't know
what what class citizens in India I
think it's an Abomination that this is a
situation it's an it's essentially India
is essentially a hinduphobic apath apad
state okay and it's unacceptable that
this still continues in the 21st century
all
right um um um um what else do we have
um sham says is the fear of hostages
holding Israel back from an allout
attack in the tunnels
look tunnels are by
Nature stealthy they're covered they're
hidden okay and and most likely Hamas
will have the entrances of the tunnels
under various buildings maybe schools
maybe universities maybe hospitals
that's what they do right so it's it's
almost impossible for Israel to use
satellite imagery and all that stuff to
find out where the tunnels begin and
where they end it's
only they would have to actually invade
Gaza physically put boots on the ground
and conduct a building by building
neighborhood by neighborhood search to
find where the tunnels are okay so
that's number one why the Israelis are
not able to attack tunnels of course
they may have spies in Gaza and they may
have some human human intelligence which
would enable them to take out certain
tunnels or or to or to you
know uh destroy certain tunnels but most
of the tunnels are are very well hidden
I would imagine okay that's number one
and when it comes to the hostages the
the the Hamas uh terrorists have taken a
large number of Israeli hostages men
women children all that I would imagine
that you know Israel has lived in a very
tough neighborhood for a very long time
I would imagine that
you know Israel would have taken the
tough decision and written these
hostages off what that means is that
they must have said to themselves that
it's very unfortunate but we have to
consider these people these hostages as
dead and then only can they otherwise
they the the hands of their military
will be tied they won't be able to do
anything they to take every step very
carefully and they can be blackmailed
the thing is you don't negotiate with
terrorists you do not you know fall prey
to the blackmail of terrorists this is
something that India has learned the
hard way uh you had
the the Indian Airlines hijacking right
remember couple of decades ago in which
uh Pakistani terrorists hijacked in
Indian irland plane which uh took off
from Katmandu
then I think it was a completely botched
operation from the Indian government
okay because we negotiated with
terrorists and uh eventually the plane
ends up in um it takes her from we
allowed it to take her fromsar it went I
think to Kandahar in Afghanistan and you
had the Taliban 1.0 in power over there
okay and the Indian government sent
another plane with and these people were
asking for the rescue for for the
release of various hostages of of of
various terrorists who were in prison in
Indian prisons and the Indian government
went ahead and did this right including
some of the great terrorists who major
terrorists who live in Pakistan today so
this is something you should never do it
shows that you are a weak State a soft
State Israel is the opposite of a soft
State India is no longer a soft state by
the way okay India is is is is a nation
that hits hits back but Israel is the
original hard State they don't negotiate
with terrorists if you take hostages
they're going to come after you and even
if the hostages die they're going to
come after you so I don't think this
fear of hostages is holding Israel back
from an all out attack in the tunnels
maybe it is other considerations it's
definitely not a fear of the hostages
getting killed I think they've most
likely written off those
hostages okay
um um Dutch fer Lind says if Trump gets
reelected reelected in 2024 will we see
any noticeable changes in the
geopolitical situation in the world
which is quite messed up as two
different Wars are going on at the same
time uh yeah we have the Middle East War
Israel Hamas hasbullah that's going on
and we have the Israel sorry the Ukraine
war as well
look let's say hypothetically president
Trump who is 45 becomes Porter 47 okay
which means that he's reelected in
2024 will we see any major geopolitical
changes as a consequence I don't think
so I don't think so and why do I say
this it's because the porus 45
presidency has shown us a lot of things
p is 45 the 46th president is Biden Mr
Biden is anybody under the illusion that
Biden is running the
country Biden is a geriatric geriatric
okay he's he's he's way past gone
mentally okay he I don't know what he
suffers from most likely Dementia or
whatever he's in no position to run a
household let alone run a country and if
you look at his vice president I mean in
case the president is incapacitated or
mentally gone the Vice President should
step in while the vice president is Miss
Kamala Harris who herself is clearly
demonstrably incompetent so neither the
president nor the Vice President are
running the country but someone's
running the country okay so this this
episode has told us that the US
president is not the person who genu who
actually runs the country there is
something I mean everyone knows it's
there it's What's called the Deep State
the foreign policy establishment and the
military industrial complex
establishment which essentially is run
out of the Pentagon right that's what
really runs the country it's an
unelected regime that is never out of
power okay whoever is the president the
president essentially serves a a very
specific role of that of that of keeping
attention away from where power really
resides um so and if you look at Trump's
first presidency 2016 to 2020 he was not
allowed to do anything that he wanted he
wanted to build a wall with Mexico
didn't happen he wanted to drain the
swamp in Washington DC well the swamp is
very much there he was not able to do to
even prick you know do a pin prick on
the on the swamp he was able to do
nothing okay his own party turned
against him why is this it's because
he's an outsider he's not a career
politician he's a businessman he's a
he's a billionaire and he somehow
accidentally won the presidency and the
US political establishment I'm sure they
see this as a mistake that they will not
allow to happen again so first of all I
see I don't really see Trump winning 24
but even if he does succeed in winning
24 I don't think he's going to be able
to to to effect any significant change
in US foreign policy I don't think it's
going to happen Okay so I don't think
there'll be any noticeable changes in
the geopolitical situation in the world
um
well as the president you you can order
your troops to do this or do do that but
if it does happen it's going to be very
minor very insignificant
and the way the US is embroiled in
various Wars it's very hard to extricate
itself out of it right now obviously
they are not fighting the Ukraine war
themselves but uh we know how things are
so I think it's going to be uh it's not
going to make much a very very major
change if Trump does come to power
again all right all right all
right explain about Native Americans the
Native Americans are the true
inhabitants and the true natives of the
of the Americas what are the
Americas these are the Americas North
America and South America which are
connected by this region the the EAS of
Panama okay
so the Native Americans are the people
who who lived who who still live some of
them still live there there but the
people who are the original natives of
these regions way before the Europeans
the whites came into the picture so the
first known contact between Europeans
and the people of the Americas happened
about a thousand years ago
when when Eric the Red a viking Explorer
first glimpsed the coast of New
Foundland in northeastern uh America
okay North America and it was his son Le
Erikson who made first landfall who
actually landed on the coast and then
the Vikings they established at least
one settlement called l omov in New
Foundland and they encountered natives
whom they called scryings and then you
later on I don't know what happened to
that those settlements and those people
maybe they maybe they got assimilated
into the native population or not we
don't know and then you had the invasion
which starts with the genocide that
Christopher col Columbus perpetrated on
the natives of what they call
Hispanola the the Carib the arabat
people and all that and then you have
the Spaniards who ravage South America
and then you have the French and the
English who ravage North America and uh
you know conservative estimates tell you
that the genocide was at least 56
million individuals over a period of 100
or 200 years most likely it was an
excess of 100 million okay and they also
wiped out the North American wild bison
so as to destroy the Native American
economy and to destroy the Native
American way of life life so the Native
Americans are well they are people who
are closely related to the Siberian
tungusic and mongolic peoples okay and
they most likely crossed over most
likely I'm saying most likely not 100%
we not 100% sure but they most likely
crossed over the bearing straight in the
during the last ice age about maybe 13
15,000 years ago when this entire region
was frozen over and and you could just
walk in to North America but it's not
like that's where that so it doesn't
mean that n that North America and South
America were settled and the process
began only 13,000 years ago because we
have found evidence of human settlements
in South America that go back more than
100,000 years more than a lack years so
history is very complicated we are still
finding new evidence but yeah that in
brief is the deal about the Native
Americans they are the true natives of
America they are now marginalized very
badly especially in North America they
are not even second class they're third
class citizens they are forced to stay
to live on res a do you want to see
reservations let's look at reservations
look at this Mescalero reservation and
you can see it's it's
uh you can see the shape straight lines
it's land that's been kept aside for
these Native Americans and they are
forced to live on that and they
essentially it's third world conditions
over there while the the Invaders and
their and settlers live in
great comfort and all that you have Nava
this Rama Navajo Indian reservation
Pueblo people the
canono Indian reservation and you see
this all across the US okay so the
Americans government will say that you
know we have set aside land for the
Native Americans we treat them with
dignity and all that but actually they
are marginalized very badly um there's
terrible racism against them the police
are very harsh on them and it's it's
just it's just a Horror Story okay and
these are the Nations that that lecture
the world about human rights so there we
have it
okay so this is a question I get like 20
times a day duti rag says when will
India take back Pakistan occupied
Kashmir from Pakistan look patience
there patience let's be
patient the what is the ideal way of of
India getting back po or whatever we
want do we want to go and fight and fire
shots and may perhaps lose a few
soldiers we don't want to do that the
IDE ideal situation is where Pakistan
dis disintegrates on its own without any
without any action from India and then
you just walk in and take back what is
yours that is the ideal situation okay
so it should happen spontaneously
organically from within Pakistan without
any Indian military involvement and that
can be engineered over time I don't see
Pakistan playing more than one more
World Cup Cricket okay this is the 2023
World Cup that we are playing right now
you have World Cup in 20 2027
I don't see them them playing the 2031
World Cup I don't think Pakistan will
will Exist by the time so it's all about
India Rising rising Rising okay and as
India Rises the foreign interference in
the region will de decline decline
decline and eventually a stage will come
where Pakistan will because of its own
internal problems break apart on its own
I mean you know so it's so we need to be
patient and we need to get this done in
the most ideal manner without firing a
single shot
ideally uh Nan ratnani says uh the
recent protest in P is it something done
by raw I would say no no no we we
Indians are very peaceloving people we
don't interfere in the internal affairs
of the Nations these protest and P are
happening because truthfully because the
people are oppressed very badly by the
isi by the Pakistan military okay people
are sick and tired and po uh about the
situation and what's happening there
look you go to
p and the people there can see across
the border how the situation is across
the border in free Jammu and Kashmir
which is Indian Jammu and Kashmir you
will find that everybody has a great
standard of living everybody has
electricity everybody has schools there
are roads built everywhere the border
road organizations roads organization is
working day and night to build more and
more infrastructure the situation is
brilliant it's it's it's superb every
kid goes to school everything is great
and across the border in Pakistan UB
Kashmir the situation is dire okay
people are oppressed there is no there
are no schools there are no hospitals
okay there's no electricity there are no
roads and wherever you have something
you have the heavy boot of the Pakistani
military on your back so people are
genuinely in po sick and tired of this
occupation they can see how much better
things are for their brothers and
sisters across the line of control and
they would want that for themselves okay
so that's why they're protesting they
are they they just Fed Up of the
Pakistani occupation they've realized
that all of this was a lie that the
Pakistan will give us freedom and
whatever rights what have they got what
have they got from Pakistan and look at
the situation in in in free Jammu and
Kashmir in which is with India where it
belongs right so I don't think it's done
by raw or anything I genuinely don't
think it's done by Raw it's it's genuine
spontaneous frustration and anger and
people are just fed up of Pakistan and
that's why I say that give it time
Pakistan will break up on its
own
okay um um um
um anur okay we back come back to the
Middle East what's your thought uh that
will the US take advantage of the Israel
Palestine conflict by attacking Iran
maybe maybe their development of
military seems the same way look it is a
possibility the Americans have always
wanted to take revenge on Iran for uh
the what they call the Iran hostage
crisis after 1979 when the ayas took
over the was the Islamic revolution in
Iran the US Embassy was besieged by
students and protesters and Iranians and
then Iranian government and uh a number
a large number of us diplomats and
operatives okay were taken as hostages
and this lasted a very long time after a
very long time they were released but
the Iranian regime looks upon the us as
Shan a bz the great devil right uh so
the US has always wanted to to punish
Iran and put Iran in its place and as we
know they have deployed there there are
large very large number of US military
bases and installations all around Iran
right uh so they will obviously would
they would obviously love to to punish
Iran take military action against Iran
and effect a regime change in thean and
and install a puet government that is
you know uh more amenable to the US
that's always the dream you know so uh
it depends whether the US will be able
to do this to take advantage of the
conflict or not so uh they'll be able to
do it if there is direct evidence or
they are able to produce any kind of
evidence of Iranian involvement in uh
the conflict we know that Hamas and
hisbah both have ties with Iran but it
will take more than that to to to to
precipitate us kinetic military action
against Iran and it's not as as easy as
it sounds I mean look at the distance
from let's say
this point in the sea in the in the pan
Gulf to tan it's
645 kilometers it's a long distance I
mean to take to to Target tan with
fighter planes or whatever it's not easy
you can use cruise missiles and all but
then your Naval assets are also
vulnerable the Iranians have the ability
to stealthily tail us warships and maybe
Target them okay so it's not as it's not
going to be a walkover so there's going
to be an element of caution but yeah
that's the great dream of the US to to
you know affect a regime change in
Iran
okay okay Kunal ding says how can trains
like vand bhat and Namo bhat help the
Indian economy to prosper you know it's
all about connectivity it's about
connecting the nation and making it easy
really easy for Indians to travel from
travel from one place to another and and
that is what bolsters the economy so for
the longest time Indian the Indian rail
network was the same as what the British
left behind so the British built the
Indian rail network and this was the
infrastructure of occupation and
extraction the purpose that the British
had for building the Indian railways was
to ensure that whatever materials and
and supplies and goods they were
stealing from India they were
transported from the interior parts of
India to the various Indian ports like
like Madras now Chennai Bombay now
Mumbai and so on right so that was that
was the whole point of the Indian
railways the built and after 1947 India
almost built almost nothing more you
know it's only after in the past decade
or so that we have see seeing a
significant uptake in the in the in the
construction of of of Highways and
Railways and all that now it's not
enough to have good sufficient railway
lines you also need to have highspeed
Railway so trains like vand bat and Namo
Bharat are not exactly highspeed trains
but semi highspeed trains so they do a
much better job instead of traveling at
50 or 60 or 70 kilm per hour they may
travel at 120 130 km per hour maybe even
110 maybe even 100 with a significant U
you know uh significant difference and
it makes things faster so for an economy
to really grow and to be really
Unleashed to its full potential the
entire nation should needs to be
interconnected let's say you're a
business person sitting in in in in uh
let's say you you're sitting in in
tirupati okay and you have a business
idea and you need to go to let's say uh
let's say you need to go to jart in
Assam now typically you will have to
take a train or something but a plane
okay and that's where all the all the
airports also come in that so many
airports are being built on on a very uh
on a war footing but even if you have a
high-speed train or semi- highspeed
train that can you know offset the the
travel traveling time then you know it
it really helps you in your business and
it it accelerates the the growth of your
business and there are certain sectors
okay in which let's let's say you want
to travel from let's say from Mumbai to
Pune okay so if you want to fly to Pune
you have to go to the airport you have
to go there at least two hours before
the flight takes off uh and traveling to
the airport will take 1 hour so that's
three hours gone and Mumbai to Puna will
be maybe 45 minutes or half an hour or
something the total traveling time for
you from the time you step out of your
house is at least 4 hours and if you
have a semi- highspeed train that can
get you there in let's say 2
hours I mean isn't it better and that to
in comfort so so that that's where all
these trains come in V bhat Namo bhat
and all that and the more of these train
routes that we build the more the Indian
population will be integrated together
and the economy will also be be be
Unleashed because of that so that's what
you know these these highspeed rail
networks and all that do that that's
what happened in China and that's what
truly Unleashed Japan okay the Japanese
economy was truly Unleashed in the 1950s
and 1960s with the building of the
shinan shinen whatever they call it the
the Japanese high-speed trains which
totally connected Japan from one end to
to the other and it totally unleashed
the Japanese economy so that's what
these these highspeed trains do and
that's what India is investing in with
with very good
reason all right what okay Ajit says I
have noticed that hitte Kings and city
names are very similar to Sanskrit names
like Pana Anita kushara how similar was
the was this language in that time
period okay so the hittite
Empire or Kingdom whatever you want to
call it it's something that
existed about around 15500 BC where did
it exist it existed in Northern Syria
and Anatolia in in in Western
Mesopotamia okay uh in this
region and and you had the the the
Hittites and you also had the
mitani and both of these
kingdoms were ruled so the the people
they spoke the hittite Lang okay let's
let's let's retrack or retrace it I
think the hittite language was what is
classified as an IND Indo Iranian
language okay and uh well when we say
Indo Iranian Indo European sorry so it
has it has its origins in the oldest
known Indo European language and uh you
know the oldest EUR Indo known
Indo-European language is obviously Vic
Sanskrit and maybe previc Sanskrit and
you also had the mitani Empire The miani
Empire had an Indo Arian Sanskrit
speaking aristocracy or ruling class
okay so this region
it is clear that about 4,000 or so years
ago or maybe 3 and a half thousand years
ago Indians traveled out of India
westwards and settled in this region and
we also have corroborate you know
supporting evidence which is the that
the same exact time where these Indian
origin kingdoms arise over here you have
the introgression of the Indian zebu
cattle in this region and they
eventually make them way into Egypt and
so on so forth long story so the
Hittites were of Indian origin the
mitani rulers were also of Indian origin
okay and that's why you have these names
if you if you see the names of the
mitani rulers for example you have twata
you have paratwa you have all these
Sanskrit origin names and you have this
horse training manual by Kuli a horse
Master of the mitani who writes in the
in the huran language but there are
certain terms in which he he has he
doesn't have the words because the
hurrian language doesn't have those
words those technical words and
therefore he has to use his own native
language for that Sanskrit Sanskrit
terminology Na and and so on so forth
you know you know numbers and various
technical terms for horse for horse
training and all that so that's the
that's the oldest attested evidence of
written Sanskrit actually which we find
in this region in in in Syria Northern
Syria and Mesopotamia and and the city
the capital city of the of the mitani it
was called wasani which is the mine of
wealth in Sanskrit so yeah very
interesting history story and it's
something that we need to we should
actually look into in Greater
depth
okay what else do we
have uh um umac says your thoughts on
the arch Botanical findings of custard
apple in bhat confirmed the barati
American contact I'm not I've not really
studied this I'm not looked into this in
detail uh it's something new that I'm
learning because of this comment so I
will look it up and maybe next time I'll
speak about this you even have you know
uh Columbus discovered the Americas in
what in 1498 was it or whichever year it
was somewhere around that time late 15th
century okay and we know that maze the
plant the crop maze is a South American
crop okay Latin South American crop but
if you look at way there are certain
Temple inscriptions in India you know
carvings of maze that
predate predate the so-called discovery
of the Americas by Columbus so yeah
there are lots of pieces of
circumstantial evidence here and there
that kind of tell you that there is more
that to all this and meets ey and maybe
the Indians had contact with the
Americas long before the Europeans uh
came to know about the Americas it's
possible right all right all
right Dean Shai says when when we search
zero was invented by which country
Mesopotamia appears what the hell is
going on is it some propaganda look when
you look at when you search on a search
engine it's going to only give you what
the
prevalent wisdom is and in the west the
prevalent wisdom is that India did
nothing and it's everything good came
out of somewhere else they even say that
the oldest Indo European language is
some some random Anatolian language or
something you know so they they try to
take the credit out of India away from
India for everything for mathematics for
zero for for oldest Indo European
language and so on so it's propaganda
it's what their historians propagate and
because it's the prevalent wisdom and
the prevalent narrative in the west
that's why it always appears on top of
all your all of your search engin and
all that so let's not get swayed by this
we know it's propaganda it is it is all
right all
right uh what else do we have there are
lots of interesting questions adiya
ravikumar says how can India impl ment
Sanskrit as a national language the goal
is for people to be able to see speak
and read Sanskrit even in the Villages
how do we accomplish this it's going to
take time it's going to be it's going to
be politically very fraud because there
is this very strong anti- Sanskrit anti-
Hinduism movement that's been built up
by the Davidian politicians in Southern
India okay uh there very strong
sentiment that's been built up and and
inculcated through the media through the
political class through various media
narratives and the education system okay
and because of this all a very
significant percentage of the people in
Southern India they see Sanskrit as a
foreign imposition on them okay even
though it is the cholas and and the
various other such Kings and dynasties
that promoted Hinduism and Sanskrit and
took it to a very large extent across
southeast Asia so yeah that's the thing
so there's a very significant population
percentage of the population in India
that is very strongly opposed to
Sanskrit so it's going to take time for
us to be able to do this we will need a
strong government and we're willing to
decolonize the minds of Indians Sanskrit
is the language the the civilization
language of all of India north south
east west all of it okay it's not some
foreign imposition but you say this to
somebody in Southern India especially in
Tamil Nadu they'll come and like they'll
see you as the enemy you are an Invader
you are prop you are trying to impose
your culture on us ours is is a separate
culture it's a secular culture we over
had Hinduism and brahminism and all that
nonsense they talk and the justification
of for all of this is the Arian Invasion
Theory which is still taught as gospel
truth in India's schools colleges and
universities so it's it's multiple
generation it's it's a multiple
generational indoctrination and
brainwashing that has been done to our
people by the education system by by
unscrupulous politicians who are doing
it for their own
benefit and that's where we find
ourselves today so it's going to be very
difficult to do it immediately Maybe
it'll take another I don't know how many
years we'll need a very strong
leadership in India to be able to start
this process okay and if it is to be
implemented it has to be implemented in
phases it has to be done through the
education system so year year One what
you do is you introduce Sanskrit as the
as the native language in the first year
of Education what we call
kindergarten Nursery the next year you
you pass it on to to to what they calls
Junior kg then Senior kg standard one so
it'll take a process of 20 years before
this you can do this but 20 years is a
very short period of time in the bigger
scheme of things so that's how you do it
yeah it has to be done through the
through the education system through
nowhere else we be able to do this but
it's going to it's going to take time
and it's going to take the right kind of
political climate to be able to achieve
this and for us to decolonize properly
because our our great civilizational
export has been Sanskrit and Hinduism
right throughout throughout the world
especially throughout southeast Asia
East Asia and all that even even
Japan H shahen vaman
Zan dud b sha greetings thank you thank
you so much appreciate it thank
you
um okay Tushar says how long will this
Gaza conflict last and how long and how
is India going to be affected by this so
listen I hope it doesn't last long but
you never know it could last long
especially if Nations get involved and
it becomes a long a slow long simmering
conflict like what you have in Ukraine
then it could last for a long time which
would be terrible for the people who
live in this region how is India going
to be affected by this look if the
conflict expands Beyond where it is it
it engulfs let's say Iran Saudi Arabia
all that then it's going to be a
disaster for the world economy because
the most of the energy of the world you
know the oil and gas comes from here
Saudi Arabia and Iran um they are two of
the major oil exporters India
the UAE also could get go get affected
by this right Oman Yemen all that we
have excellent relations with Saudi
Arabia if Saudi Arabia let's say is at
War for whatever reason and if the
Iranians are at war with the US and they
and let's say they choke off they they
cut off the the the straight of hormos
which connects the Persian Gulf with the
Indian Ocean then that could uh you know
cut send oil prices skyrocketing it
could be a big problem for India okay
that's one thing
the other thing is that one of the major
outcomes of the G20 Summit okay was the
India middle east Europe trade and
transportation coridor which was
supposed to hit the ground running and
start within a month of the end of the
summit the Saudis wanted to wanted it to
the construction to start right away but
now but this imch this Corridor was
supposed to pass through the UAE Saudi
Arabia Jordan Israel and then move on to
Greece and bypass turkey but now that
this conflict is happening exactly in
the wrong place the India middle east
Europe trade and transportation Corridor
it's its construction will not start
now so this Corridor was supposed to be
a game Cher a genuine viable alternative
to the Chinese built and Road BR thing
right but see now it's not happening
right now it may still happen in the
future once things settle down hopefully
so these are various ways in which India
is going to be affected by this not just
India but the whole world because let's
say in the next by by 2030 we have a
very strong Corridor ready over here the
imech then it's going to benefit India
it's going to benefit Europe and it's
going to benefit the middle east region
as well the Gulf region as well and
India could similarly create another
Corridor which will connect India all
the way to Japan or austral even
Australia you know in some way or other
uh multimodal Corridor so yeah you know
so these conflicts especially the the
conflict that happens in the Middle East
region is going to have repercussions
all across the world so just just that's
just two or three ways in which you
could India is going to be affected by
this and not just India but the entire
world yeah so so you gotta so these
things are important and India needs to
keep a very close watch on what's
Happening and be proactive in taking
actions to prevent too much of this
problem from spilling over and affecting
India Anisha says Maldives new PM is
given ultimative for Indians to leave
your views about maldiv in India
relations in the future look uh maldiv
is is kind of a place where you have
this geopolitical proxy conflict
happening between India and China
okay so the Maldives are essentially an
extension of the lakad AR
archipelago uh if you go west of of
uh of Kerala you have the lakad
archipelago
and that is it's something that goes
right into into the Maldives AR
archipelago which goes all the way south
and actually the the end point of the
males is Diego Garcia which is currently
occupied with the Americans and the and
the British okay that's a whole
different story so Maldives is a is a
strategically important reason region
sorry region country Nation whatever you
want to call it and historically it's
been part of the Indian civilization
Indian subcontinent right uh now the
Chinese have been eyeing this region for
a very long time the Chinese as we know
they have been trying to encircle India
at Sea by creating this string of Naval
bases that kind of encircles India uh
you know they they they have Haman to in
Sri Lanka you know we know we all know
this I'm sure the good old String of
Pearls strategy and Maldives is one of
the components that they would like to
incorporate into the String of Pearls so
males is a place where you have this
proxy conflict happening between India
and China the Chinese are very good at
this they will simply offer unlimited
amounts of money to a politician who is
pliable and willing to do their bidding
so there are certain politicians in
Maldives certain parties that are
pro-china and some are more
nationalistic and pro India so now
there's this new election and this new
prime minister has coming and he wants
Indians to leave
so so what India needs to do is India
needs to get stronger India needs to
build its economy build up its Navy
okay uh this see the Indian Indian
government Indian Navy keeps on saying
that the Indian Ocean region is our
strategic backyard well words and
slogans will not make it India's
strategic backyard we need to have a
significant not significant a massive
Naval presence of visible Naval presence
in this region at all times so whenever
a foreign Ship Sails through this
through this region they should see the
Indian presence and say that oh my God
now yeah yeah this is a place where you
have Indians everywhere Indian Naval
assets everywhere so that's what India
needs to do once India does that the
Chinese presence will naturally decrease
okay and because it is close to India we
will have the upper hand and then once
you have the upper hand navally and your
Navy is present everywhere these local
politicians will also behave themselves
they'll be more they'll be they'll be
more inclined to behave themselves and
be be more Pro India and of course India
needs to play The Diplomatic game as
well and whatever the Chinese do we need
to count that in a variety of ways so
right now Maldives is a place like like
I said earlier that the sahil region of
Africa is kind of the place where the
new cold war is unfolding it's being
played out between the US between France
between Russia and China you know
everybody is weying is is weying for
Supremacy in every country over here
similarly a similar thing is happening
in the Maldives between India and China
so if India plays plays its cards right
then the Chinese will will slowly lose
their influence in the region similarly
we are seeing something similar
happening in Nepal as well and because
of the blunders of the Indian government
in the 1990s um the the Hindu monarchy
of Nepal was destroyed and the the
maoists the Communists the anti-
Indian terrorists essentially came to
power in Nepal but that's what happened
and because of this Nepal kind of became
more and more pro-china that that's
that's the situation today it's entirely
because of the stupid ridiculous
policies of the Indian government of of
that time so yeah so there are lots of
problems that we are facing today which
are a consequence of the blunders of
previous governments now we have to find
ways of solving them and it's going to
take time so I would say that India and
Maldives the relations right now are
kind of like this Maldives is a place
where you have a proxy conflict
happening a conflict you know there is
this battle for influence that's going
on in the Maldives it's going to be a
while maybe 10 20 years before India can
properly take the opp hand in this
region
okay okay Shar Chri says why hasn't
Russia used its Air Force enough in
Ukraine like Israel is doing now in Gaza
see it it's it's it's all because of
what objectives Russia has in Ukraine
Russia Russia doesn't want to flatten
Ukraine and then take over a wasteland
okay that's not what Russia wants Russia
may not even want to Annex the whole of
Ukraine or even half of Ukraine they've
okay let's go back to the map so the
Russians uh have taken over the donbas
region right Lans donet all all these
regions uh they had taken K also they
withdrew from there and it's long story
so Russia I don't think they ever wanted
to flatten Ukraine destroy Ukraine
completely and then take over a
wasteland they don't even they have even
tried their best to minimize civilian
casualties of course in a war civilian
will unfortunately die okay that's just
the nature of warfare but they did their
best from day one to minimize civilian
casualties so typically when the
Americans let's say when the Americans
invaded Iraq in 1991 or 2003 what they
did was they slammed millions of I would
not say Millions but tens of thousands
of tons of bombs hundreds of thousands
of tons of bombs into cities like Bagdad
with no consideration for civilian
casualties and they live streamed
everything on CNN right so that's what
the Americans do they use the what they
call the shock and O tactics they
flatten entire nations and then they
make sure that no civilian casualties
are shown on TV that's what they do the
Russians did not want that at all they
wanted to take Ukraine as intact as
possible ideally they just want to
change the regime in Kev get rid of
zinsky and put a puet government in
place which would be Pro Russia Pro
Russia and then make sure that Ukraine
becomes a neutral power which is
essentially a buffer against the NATO
regions in the west that's what Russia
wants and of course they don't want to
risk their their air assets they have a
very powerful Air Force but they don't
want to risk it they have used
helicopters and maybe a few Suk or migs
here and there older versions but they
have not really used the Air Force so
what is the Russian objective the
Russian objective is to affect regime
change in Kiev uh get rid of the Western
influence in in Ukraine and make and
install a pro Russia puppet government
in Kiev get rid of zalinski okay zinski
can go and live in the west and enjoy
his billions um and maybe some part of
Ukraine maybe Western Ukraine could even
eventually reunify with Poland and
that's a whole different story which we
will not go into right now so that's
what Russia actually wants and they want
to do this with minimum casualties
obviously casualties are going to be
high if you have a two-year plus War
which is is L right know right now but
they want to have as few casualties as
possible they want to fight as little as
possible and achieve their objectives
why while doing so um and now things are
Meandering in Ukraine as we know right
right now the whole focus is down south
in the Middle East region in Israel and
Gaza uh the billions of dollars that
were flowing in to is into into Ukraine
from the US that money is now slowing
down to a trickle and very soon and and
and and and and Ukraine has suffered
such incredible catastro trophic losses
in its armed forces that you know the
armed forces are very badly depleted
they are dependent completely dependent
on the west for arms and ammunition and
and all kinds of supplies now that it's
slowing down to trickle so now it's
essentially unless the the supply start
again it's essentially a matter of time
before Ukraine Falls okay and the
Russians will eventually just be able to
walk into Kiev and change the regime or
do something like that it may take six
months it may take the next three years
but it it if things continue the way
they are right now that's what's going
to happen so so then why why you use the
Air Force just let it just just be
patient and wait for Ukraine to fall
into your lap that that would be the
Russian perspective on this so that's
why Russia has not used its Air Force it
does the Russian government I don't
think they see the ukrainians as enemies
they see the ukrainians as their own
people which they actually are okay so
these are the reasons why they are not
behaving the way
Israel is behaving in Gaza or the way
the US has behaved historically in
whatever Nations it has
invaded all
right uh Benzene says why is it so
difficult to produce Crystal blades for
fighter jet engines so you know when you
have a fighter jet or any jet engine you
inside a jet engine you have incredibly
high temperatures way higher than the
melting point of steel or iron or
whatever and you have very high
pressures as well and your turbine
blades need to be able to withstand
those temperatures and perform for hours
and hours at a at a stretch okay and
then do all over again do that all over
again and then all over again every time
the plane flies so you need to be able
to produce
materials that uh whose whose whose uh
properties are such that they can
withstand incredibly high temperatures
and pressures temperatures and pressur
that that would destroy any normal steel
uh
blade or or or or aluminum or or or iron
whatever right so you need exotic
materials you need to be able to build
exotic material so what what they do is
that they produce these turbine blades
out of a single Crystal of metal single
Crystal and that Crystal has been has to
be grown from a nucleation point if you
study chemistry or or Material Science
you know that Crystal is grown inside
out out of a single nucleation point and
it's a very well it's it's it's very
high-tech it's a very difficult process
okay and uh this is something this
technology is something that's that's
been developed in the west certain
companies have this technology Rolls
Royce I'm I'm sure they have it uh saf
of
France has it uh and certain other
nations would have it it's something
they've only been able to develop
through lots of trial and error and this
process took decades it took decades
okay so that's the deal it's not easy to
produce jet engine uh jet engines that
can produce at that can perform at the
the the highest level yeah it's it's a
process of painstaking trial and error
trial and error you need to invest in
Material Science you need to invest in
Ceramics you need to invest in exotic
materials you need a big research pool
of scientists who do all this research
you need to invest in the right kind of
labs invest hundreds of millions of
dollars in in building these labs and
having all this technology it takes time
and takes a lot of money and a lot of
effort okay and obviously when it comes
to India we previous governments were
all about okay we don't have it why why
should we develop it on on our own let's
just buy it and we let actually make
some money in the process let's buy jet
engines why why make our own jet engine
why develop our own figh fighter planes
let's just buy fighter planes and we'll
get nice Kickbacks so that's how it's
always been in India a lot of corrup and
lot of I mean they just didn't care
about the nation I'm not singling out or
pointing fingers at any specific
government or individual I'm just saying
that's how it was generally and that has
changed only in the recent past and now
if we were to start the process of
developing a you know a jet engine that
would be able to that we we could use on
let's say the amca or any other future
fighter plane that process could take at
least a decade maybe two decades that's
just how it is it takes time it's not
something that you throw money at it and
throw money let's say I throw $500
million at it and then I'll in six
months I'll get a jet engine that's not
how it works takes time so that's why
it's so difficult it's such a difficult
technology such a uh that's the
technology is so Advanced okay it takes
a lot of trial and error so that's just
how it
is uh arunima shast says I from Nepal my
country is suffering from Christian
missionaries they started converting
Hindus hugely uh Muslim population also
increasing here it's scary look I'm
aware this entire process started after
the earthquake so you had this
earthquake in Nepal which year was it a
few years ago five six seven years ago
terrible earthquake in Nepal lots of
people died lots of Destruction and I
could see this chatter on social media
among the Evangelist groups that these
nepales temples have fallen down now
churches should come up in their place
so it's yeah it's
it's yeah that's just that's it's just
what they do they're called Soul
vultures right I mean you know I have
nothing against a person converting from
one religion to another if that need for
conversion that spiritual need comes
from within it should be your own choice
but what these people do is that they
off they go to these poverty stricken
countries or or countries where some
recent tragedy Like An Earthquake has
happened and in exchange for Aid they
require the people to convert that's
what they do it is that's why they
called Soul vultures so this is horrible
and looks like the nepales government is
turning a blind eye to this so it's very
unfortunate um yeah so uh I'm I'm glad
that you are mentioning this here the
world needs to know that the indigenous
culture is under threat the indigenous
culture that's 10,000 plus years old the
indigenous nepales culture Hindu
Hinduism is under threat they're trying
to eradicate it which is happening in
other parts of India also but I think we
are a very ancient civilization all of
us and eventually in the long run we
will prevail
especially as India gets more powerful
we'll be able to hopefully give some Aid
the right kind of Aid you know to to all
of our neighbors all of our Civ
spiritual
civilizational uh Brethren so yeah I
hope things get better but currently
that's the situation that is indeed the
situation
yeah uh um
uh JP FR one second let me just deal
with uh an
individual
okay J says how can I please stop sing
and worshipping women as male s for
women women's rights issues sometimes I
get accused of being a male SIM can you
please teach me on how to stop
[Music]
I I I I don't don't know I mean there's
nothing wrong with uh liking women I
mean I I guess what you mean by sing is
you put too much value in the other
person or something like that I guess
what you need to do is become more
confident and and and develop yourself
as an individual and see that there is a
huge amount of value in yourself
yourself as well so that you don't feel
like you are worthless and every other
person let's say women are are are you
know like a million times more valuable
than you see all humans have some
intrinsic value and it is something we
can develop on our own so I I would say
that if you feel this way maybe you feel
some sense of sense of in inadequacy in
yourself because of whatever reason I
don't know what it could or could not be
because I don't know you personally I
would say try and introspect and find
and ask yourself what is it you feel
about yourself where do you feel that
you are inadequate and then work on that
then work on that you know you can
always grow as a as an individual and
grow as a human being and whatever your
weaknesses are you can turn them into
your strength as well so for example
some just just a random example maybe
maybe you feel feel that you're not
physically strong enough I'm just saying
some people may feel that way well go to
the gym LIF lift weights eat well give
it six months and you will be a
different person or one year or two
years right so it's something you can
all work on yourselves I would just say
that introspect spend some time
understanding yourself understand
understanding who you are what your
strengths are what your weaknesses are
where you feel that you're inadequate
and then work on that give it time it it
won't you won't change over a week's
time give yourself two years in two
years you'll be a totally transformed
person if you are consistent in working
on yourself so so that's what I would
say so the main thing is you have value
good value intrinsic value every human
being has value on their own and
everybody has strength and weaknesses
you got to work on his strengths and try
to eliminate you can't eliminate all
weaknesses but you can reduce them so
that's what I would
say shantanu ja says will India get a
permanent seat in the UN and have V of
power how many years will it take Accord
to you I simply don't care if India
doesn't get gets or doesn't get a
permanent seat in the UN or has youo
power the thing is this see the UN
Security Council permanent members there
are five of them and that situation
represents the the way the world was in
1945 almost a century ago so that it
reflects an outdated obsolete World
Order okay my point is this I simply
don't care whether we get this un
permanent seat or not because if we rise
and we become strong enough then it
won't matter whether we have a seat or
not because our strength itself will be
such that this veto power won't matter
we'll have a de facto veto power in the
world if you're strong enough if we
become a 20 trillion economy or 25
trillion economy um India eventually if
we play our cards right we're going to
be the largest economy in the world in
this century when you are the largest
economy in the world we have you're
going to have a military that is
proportional to that strength then you
have a veto whether you whether people
give you a veto or not you have it on
your own so my point point is forget
about stop begging for the UN permanent
the seat in the UN Security Council stop
lobbying for it stop stop stop craving
for it work on yourself like I said that
is you got to identify your strength and
weaknesses we have tremendous potential
in India we can rise to to unimaginable
levels if you all work together so
that's what we need to focus on give it
some time the world is yours and this
won't matter
anymore okay
um okay lots of other questions lots of
other questions
um uh what
else
[Music]
uh okay let's see this Indian rupe is
falling day by day really is
it can you explain how the value is
decided and is this a concern for India
or is it befitting us uh let me go and
let us go to our friend Mr googal and
look at the Indian rupee okay INR to USD
is it falling really let's see this INR
to
USD
um what about five years it's not really
falling continuously but yeah you could
say that yeah over time it has
fallen it has fallen over time so how
does this happen see in a free floating
Market the the uh it all depends on the
the the demand that you have obviously
when you have the US dollar the US
dollar is a paper currency it's a fiat
currency it's something that uh is the
world's Reserve currency and it can be
manipulated by the
Americans at
will uh so yeah this is a complex topic
and I'm not quite an expert in economics
but I would say I would
say that there are lots of things India
can do to strengthen the the the Indian
currency one one of the ways is to buy
up more gold the other way is to
increase your GDP the outport there are
lots of things we can do uh I don't
think this is overall a matter of great
concern unless you the The rupe Falls
precipitously which would indicate a
serious systemic problem for example
Pakistani rupe to USD you will see that
Pakistani
rupee so that is a total disaster you
can see it's it's Fallen Pakistan rupe
to INR I mean even that if you
see you can see how how badly it's
fallen and the fall
begins uh sometime in 2016 2017 so you
know these are complex things but I
don't see this as a matter of concern
this is a long-term game and eventually
the Indian rupee see the Indian rupee
will do well what what the Americans are
doing is they at at any given point in
time if they feel that they need to
manipulate the global economy in a
certain way they will print a few
trillion trillion dollars here and there
just just invent money out of thin air
in your computers that's what the
Americans do and because their currency
is the reserve currency they they have
the power to do it eventually it won't
be that way uh the world is now kind of
tired of this situation and the process
of dollarization may actually happen in
the next 10 20 years so
yeah
okay Arian Shaw says yeah let's talk
about
aliens uh what do you think about alien
bodies found in Mexico well
look there's this claim okay that alien
uh mummies have been found in Mexico and
the the the I don't know who it was but
some University in Mexico and so on they
came out with this claim they put out
some videos and some some images and all
that okay so that's a claim they have
made a claim now here's the scientific
process when someone makes a claim that
claim has to be independently verified
so another team of scientists or maybe
multiple team of teams of scientists who
are unrelated and unconnected with the
people making the claim these other
teams of scientists should be given the
same information the same data the same
evidence and they should be asked to
examine it independently and give their
own scientific opinion based on
scientific testing and evidence whether
these are actual ill artifact or whether
these are Fabrications so that is called
peer review the proper way of doing peer
review you know independent peer review
that's not
happened so if so when you make a claim
but you don't allow anyone to either
prove it or or or debunk it that's just
a claim and that cannot be taken as as
as gospel truth it cannot be taken as um
proven right uh so that's that's that's
my perspective on this what what do I
think I think somebody has made a claim
but we we don't know if that claim is
true is a genuine claim or whether it is
a fabrication I I would say it's more
likely it's a fabrication given the
entire
history of these claims of alien
visitations and all that till today
nobody has been able to prove with be
you know
give incontrovertible proof of any alien
presence on this planet not a single one
I people give you photographs people
give you videos but it's typically
grainy photographs taken by one person
or or blurry videos taken by one person
okay why doesn't it ever happen that
there is this alien phenomenon that's a
UFO whatever that happens in Mumbai and
like five 50,000 people see it at the
same time and they all take take out
their phones and capture it that's
genuine
because 50,000 people saw it at the same
time or why doesn't it happen over Tokyo
or Mexico City why is it always some
random isolated place where one person
takes a picture so you know that that
that's why why I'm am very skeptical
about these things so what do I think
about these alien bodies as claim I I'm
very skeptical okay they if it is
genuinely the case they found something
they should make it this these artifacts
and this evidence available to teams of
scientists from across the world let
five different teams independent teams
of scientists come and examine the
evidence and do whatever tests they want
to do and then give their own report of
what they think this is based on
empirical evidence that's not happening
and that's why I'm very
skeptical when will India have a great
leader who will un unite the
subcontinent maybe it is going to happen
sooner rather than later okay we may be
going in the direction where such
leaders will such leaders may already be
there they may actually even be known to
people but
the they will know how good of a leader
or not they are only when they actually
come to power but I think we are going
in the direction uh Indians are becoming
more and more aware of History Indians
are becoming more and more aware of the
great history of Indian civilization
there is more and more Pride that is
slowly Awakening among Indians of all
across India and uh h when this happens
you know the quality of leadership goes
up and and leaders also have to you know
justify when a leader comes to power
they also have to live up to the
expectations of the people so I think
it's going to
happen sooner rather than later that you
will have a great leader who may unify
the subcontinent I will not give in time
frames and all because who knows I'm not
I'm not Nostradamus but yeah you you
know there are these geopolitical
experts who make predictions and then
they go on Twitter and everywhere and
say see I predicted this I predicted
that I don't do predictions I do
analysis
so
okay
uh uh anik says why is there no update
on the Russia Ukraine conflict nothing
new is happening over there is this a
sign of major attack or operation Mar
Russia coming up like I said this is a
country that's Meandering and now the
West seems to be losing interest in
Ukraine
Ukraine was always a disposable asset
for them you know it's like a pawn
sacrifice on the chessboard zilinski is
another disposable minion for them and
uh look I think right now the the amount
of Western Aid that's flowing into
Ukraine is now slowing down to a trickle
whether it is money whether it is arms
whether it is ammunition and when the
ammunition runs out then how do you
fight how do you fight a war so so
that's what's happening nothing much is
happening there the Russians are not
trying to do any major escalation of the
war they just trying to wait this out
and they just want to wait until Ukraine
has nothing left no arms no ammunition
no soldiers yeah that's what the
Russians are waiting for they're waiting
for Ukraine to fall into their lap when
why go and fight of terrible battles
when you can just wait for two three
years and everything will will fall into
your lap the way you want it so that is
what's happening right now there's no
major attack or operation that I see
coming up obviously I can be completely
wrong and Mr Putin may may prove me
completely wrong and make me look like a
fool but I from from where things are
today I don't see any major Russian
operation coming up and maybe it's very
stupid to say this because tomorrow
something may come up but let's
see right
okay okay where are
we
um so once again war between Russia and
Ukraine will it end by the end of this
year who knows who knows look we are
already in October October is ending now
but we got two months left for the for
for for this year I don't think it's
going
to most likely it won't end by the end
of this year most likely it could end
next year it could take three months it
could take three years who knows right
the way things go but when certain
specific conditions
are uh
when when certain conditions become true
when certain specific conditions are
satisfied the Russians will will move in
until then they will not try to risk any
major escalation that's what I would say
and what conditions are these that the
ukrainians run out of ammunition then
you may have guns and all that you run
out bullets and what you do so the
Russians can just walk in then right so
that sort of thing you win without
fighting ideally obviously there's been
a lot of fighting the past two years but
going forward they want to minimize the
fighting and and take
things take the country without with
minimal
fighting
okay
um yeah
aush Qatar has wrongfully imprisoned our
soldiers how to deal with them I I spoke
about this in depth in the beginning of
this thing so once this is over you can
uh rewatch that yeah I spoke about
that
can you elaborate on shrii Neu G's
rejection of Nepal rejoining India so
yeah um in the
1950s the king of Nepal King truan
wanted Nepal to rejoin India and become
an Indian State and Mr Neu he rejected
this this this proposal right and it's
not me claiming this it is former
president pranam mukarji has written
about this in his book by the way okay
check it out check out the book there's
plenty of evidence that this actually
happened so what do I say I don't know I
I simply don't understand what Mr Neu
was trying to do okay with all his
decisions giving away two what 80% of
the Indus Rivers Waters to
Pakistan allowing allowing supplying
rice to the Chinese soldiers who was
starving in their attempt to to invade
and Conquer Tibet he supplied rice to
them okay not Tak any action when the
Chinese built a road through aai chin I
mean I don't know what Mr NE was doing I
mean like the list just goes on and on
and on and on giving up guad he was
given guad for free by the Sultan of
Oman he said no we don't want it I mean
giving up a significant portion of the
kingdom of Manipur to the burmes for no
reason whatsoever as if it is his own
personal family property giving away the
Coco Island to Burma the list goes on I
mean so I don't know I mean as as the
leader of of a country you have one job
your job is to serve the nation and its
people and ensure the long-term
Prosperity every action that you take
should should contribute to
strengthening the nation and serving the
nation's
interests with with Mr Neu every action
that he took worked in the opposite way
it hurt India it harmed India long term
I mean he went to the UN and he
prevented the Indian army from retaking
po if he had waited another week India
the Indian army would have taken po back
Mr n said no stop so and and and that
the consequences of that that decision
we are still dealing with those
consequences today so I just don't know
I I don't somebody should perhaps
psychoanalyze Mr Neu based on all the
information that's available in the
public domain but I I I just don't know
why he did these things okay I simply
don't know I simply don't understand
doesn't make any sense doesn't compute
that's not what a leader is supposed to
do unless who knows what
okay
um frustration is is real is Durham is
real is yuan is
Rubble Dr s Dr janga supremasi raises a
very good question here yes ma'am how
come patriotic Indian billionaires fund
leftwing universities Harvard University
for example you have Indian billionaires
who give significant donations to these
universities and these universities then
use that money to fund anti-india
narratives anti-india research
hinduphobic research okay and there are
these private universities in India that
are funded by Indian billionaires and if
you see the kind of godamn research is
being done there all anti-india
narratives hinduphobic narratives okay
so then the question really the real
question is are these Indian
billionaires
patriotic or are they anti-nationals
that's the question we to ask ourselves
yeah so it is an in indisputable fact
that these billionaires fund the
universities everyone knows this it's
out there in the public domain anyone
can look it up then the the only
question is what is the purpose and why
are they doing it
are they truly patriotic or are they
anti-nationals I leave the answer to
yourself to you all I I leave that
answer to you you are all wise enough to
to answer it let me know in the comments
let let me let me sorry what is this uh
let me know in in in the live chat what
do you think thoughts on Jordan Peterson
H right Jordan Peterson uh what do I
think of him a Christian fundamental
Christian supremacist white supremacist
that's what I think of
him
um okay we have gone way past two hours
which is something we typically
do uh so with that done let's take maybe
one or two more
questions the world economic Forum wants
to destroy the diversity of humans
rather than protecting every last
nationality you know what makes the
world beautiful diversity is what makes
the world beautiful if you go travel
across the world and you see people who
wear the same clothes who eat the same
food and speak the same language and
worship the same religion and watch the
same TV shows and eat the same food then
what's what's the point of traveling
it's everything becomes the same dull
monotonous uniform a monoculture what
makes the world beautiful is this
diversity of culture diversity of ways
of life diversity of clothing diversity
of Cuisine diversity of languages that
diversity of religions diversities of
point of view that's what makes the
world beautiful and and these there are
these forces in the world that want to
destroy this diversity so
yeah diversity is what makes the world
beautiful and interesting and we should
cherish that and preserve
that
um
okay um let's take one last question one
last question
um views on yadam Indus Valley script
decipherment um yeah maybe I should get
him on the podcast and have him explain
it in detail which will also uh help me
understand this better so yeah let me do
that
yep
um thoughts on current India visit of
Mahi Hassan so this Mahi Hassan is a
Hindu phobe okay he thinks that Hindus
are animals
he has made very very crude very very uh
unacceptable statements in the past okay
and he has been invited to India to
Mumbai for the Tata lit Fest if I'm not
mistaken so this's this question asked
by Dr J sha Supremacy that lady right
about Indian billionaires funding left
wi universities well here you have the
tatas an Indian billionaire group who
are funding the visit of an anti- India
guy to India so what does it tell you
about the tatas what does it tell you
about the tatas
right are they Patriots or are they
Internationals I'm not saying anything
I'm asking a question please let me know
what you
think
okay uh ishwar triar says it's my
birthday happy birthday happy birthday
fantastic Bobby says two state three
states two states one state solution of
current situation I do not even know
what to say uh two State seems to make
sense but then the the point of the
Palestinian movement is from The River
To The Sea they want Palestine from The
River To The Sea okay what do they mean
by that let me explain what they mean by
that River to the Sea one second let me
U bring the map back
on okay the Palestinians want Palestine
from The River To The Sea so is that a
two State solution three state solution
one state solution which river are they
talking about they're talking about the
River Jordan okay the West Bank is the
West Bank of the River Jordan where is
this River one
second uh
yeah where's the Jordan River so this is
the Jordan River right from the river to
the Sea they want Palestine from this
from this point all the way to the Sea
which means they want the eradication
and the destruction of the nation state
of
Israel all of this they want it to be
Israel so who are
the the Palestinians are Arabs aren't
they aren't there enough Arab countries
in the world do the Jews not deserve a
single country so I don't know so let's
say we go for a two-state solution we
create a separate Palestine separate
Israel will the Palestinians be happy
with that it's it's it's kind of asking
yourselves okay hypothetically in the
1990s if the Indian government had given
away Kashmir to Pakistan would that have
solved the India Pakistan problem no
Pakistan will never be satisfied until
they destroy the whole of India the
solution is the destruction of
Pakistan right so India Pakistan was a
two-state
solution this this but you still have
this conflict and the conflict will
exist as long as Pakistan exists so we
are very clear now in India what the
what the solution is it's the
disintegration of Pakistan hopefully
peacefully yeah now so so I don't know
what's the solution to the to the Middle
East thing the Israel Palestine thing a
fair solution would be a two-state
solution obviously yeah give some land
to the Palestinians live there your West
Bank Gaza whatever it is and live the
let the let the Jews live in peace in
the other part of the region I mean it
is their ancestral Homeland
Judea right but yeah I don't think the
Palestinians will be quite happy with
that they want the destruction of Israel
so this is I don't see I don't know what
the solution is yeah I don't know what
the solution is right now okay okay okay
with that said let us end today's thing
today live stream ask abijit 169 it's
been 2 hours 11 minutes and Counting
thank you so much for all of your
questions obviously there are so many
questions I could not take so I
apologize to those of you those
questions I could not take I apologize
to those those of you ask questions in
the comments and I could not take them
but I will keep on doing this and uh
yeah we will continue this for the
foreseeable future the ask Abit show so
thank you very much for your viewership
for your support for everything and I
will see you as as soon as I possibly
can in the next episode thank you take
care bye-bye see see you soon